ramboll.com 2019-09-02

# Privacy Policy - Ramboll Group

## Websites

Ramboll's websites are accessible for the purpose only of providing general information regarding Ramboll Group A/S (in Danish also referred to as Rambøll Gruppen A/S) and its subsidiaries, and is made in accordance with Danish law.

Any data and information made accessible by these websites is made available on an "As is" and "As available" basis without any warranty or representations, either expressed or implied. Access to this website and the downloading of data and information from such website are at the user’s own risk.

All data, information or other proprietary notices are protected by copyright and together displayed with trademarks, logo etc, will remain the property of Ramboll.

Images on this website are the property of Ramboll unless otherwise specified. These images may be downloaded and used free of charge, providing that all intellectual property rights are adhered to and Ramboll is cited as the source of such image. Images from other sources may not be used without the owner's permission/consent.

Users of Ramboll websites are temporarily permitted to download and store one or more pages for viewing purposes only. Any other use, including reproduction, permanent storage, or retransmission, of the contents of this website is prohibited without the prior written consent of Ramboll Group A/S. Ramboll Group A/S and any of its subsidiaries are under no circumstances liable – whether direct, indirect or consequential - for any loss or damage arising out of the use or reliance of any data or information available at or accessible from any of the Ramboll Group A/S’ websites. This legal notice shall be governed by Danish law. Any dispute arising out of or in connection with this legal notice, or concerning the contents of any data or information made available to users of this website and websites made accessible by this website shall, unless solved amicably, be decided exclusively by the Danish Courts in Copenhagen, Denmark.

## Information we automatically collect

We automatically collect statistical information regarding website traffic. Part of this information is collected through the use of cookies. A cookie is a small text file saved to your computer and allows our website to follow your visit and to recognise your computer when you visit our website again. A cookie is not a program and does not contain virus, nor spreads malicious software. Cookies will be used to measure traffic, develop and improve our web services. 

We may use cookies to save your preferences or language to provide a better experience on our websites.

We automatically log the following information about your visit:

  * Internet Protocol (IP) address & Internet Service Provider
  * geography
  * time of access
  * browser type and language
  * operating system
  * screen resolution
  * the web page you visited before our site

We collect information about your usage and activity on our sites e.g. visited pages, words searched for in our site search engine and whether your computer/browser has previously accessed our sites.

The information collected by these cookies is stored on servers in Denmark, and will not be used for any other purposes than to help improve the services it provides to our users and for internal reporting in Ramboll. We use our own products, and products of third parties acting on our behalf, to analyse, optimise and improve our sites.

## Newsletters and marketing materials

You can choose to sign up for Ramboll electronic newsletters and marketing materials (brochures, magazines, and presentations) containing information regarding Ramboll’s services, by registering your email address, name, position and company name. By registering for electronic newsletters, you agree to the disclosure of information to the third-party provider, who hosts the newsletters. To receive newsletters and marketing materials in hard copy, you will also be asked to register a postal address.

The personal data collected as part of the registration for newsletters and marketing materials will only be used to send these items. The personal data will only be accessed on a need to know basis by those individuals within Ramboll that are responsible for the newsletters and marketing materials and will be treated as confidential. The consent to the storage of this personal data may be revoked at any time. For the purpose of revoking consent, a corresponding link is found in each electronic newsletter. It is also possible to unsubscribe from newsletters or marketing materials at any time by contacting [privacy@ramboll.com](mailto:privacy@ramboll.com).

## Events

When signing up to events hosted by Ramboll or with Ramboll participation, you are asked to register your email address, phone number, postal address, first and last names, position and place of work.

The personal data collected as part of the registration for events will only be accessed on a need to know basis by those individuals within Ramboll that are responsible for arranging the events and will be treated as confidential. The data will only be used for the purpose that the user signed up for and you can opt out of Ramboll events at any time by contacting [privacy@ramboll.com](mailto:privacy@ramboll.com) and your information will be deleted accordingly.

## Cookies used on our sites

Ramboll uses Google Analytics, which are web analytics services. These provide us with statistical information about users. Google Analytics process anonymised IP addresses and information from cookies used on the Ramboll websites, so that we know how many page views these have, the number of users, what browsers users are using (so that we can target resources in the right way to maximise compatibility for the majority of users) and in which country, city or region users are located.

## Third party cookies

We sometimes embed photos and video content from websites such as YouTube. As a result, when you visit a page with content embedded from other websites, you may be presented with cookies from these websites. Ramboll does not control the dissemination of these cookies. You should check the relevant third-party website for more information about their use of cookies.

All our websites use embedded "share" buttons to enable users to easily share information with friends through a number of popular social networks. These sites may set a cookie when you are also logged in to their service. Ramboll does not control the dissemination of these cookies and you should check the relevant third-party website for more information about their use of cookies.

Act-On Marketing is a marketing automation tool. This will only process data after you have actively submitted a form and explicitly opted-in.

We use [Hotjar](http://www.hotjar.com/) in order to better understand our users’ needs and to optimize this service and experience. Hotjar is a technology service that helps us better understand our users experience (e.g. how much time they spend on which pages, which links they choose to click, what users do and don’t like, etc.) and this enables us to build and maintain our service with user feedback. Hotjar uses cookies and other technologies to collect data on our users’ behavior and their devices (in particular device's IP address (captured and stored only in anonymized form), device screen size, device type (unique device identifiers), browser information, geographic location (country only), preferred language used to display our website). Hotjar stores this information in a pseudonymized user profile. Neither Hotjar nor we will ever use this information to identify individual users or to match it with further data on an individual user. For further details, please see Hotjar’s privacy policy by clicking on [this link](https://www.hotjar.com/legal/policies/privacy).

  You can opt-out to the creation of a user profile, Hotjar’s storing of data about your usage of our site and Hotjar’s use of tracking cookies on other websites by following [this opt-out link](https://www.hotjar.com/legal/compliance/opt-out). 

## The use of Google Maps on our websites

Ramboll and Google agrees to the Google Maps Controller-Controller Data Protection Terms at <https://privacy.google.com/businesses/mapscontrollerterms/>. Users are bound by the [Google Maps/Google Earth Additional Terms of Service](https://maps.google.com/help/terms_maps.html) (including the [Google Privacy Policy](https://policies.google.com/privacy)).

## How to reject or delete cookies

If you wish to restrict or block the cookies which are set by our websites, or indeed any other website, you can do this through your browser settings. The Help function within your browser should tell you how. 

Alternatively, you may wish to visit <http://www.aboutcookies.org.uk/> which contains comprehensive information on how to do this on a wide variety of browsers. You will find details on how to delete cookies from your computer as well as more general information about cookies. For information on how to do this on the browser of your mobile phone you will need to refer to your handset manual.

Please be aware that restricting cookies may impact the functionality of the Ramboll websites.

## Personal information

When you use this website Ramboll Group A/S will as data controller collect, store, or use personally identifiable data about you such as name, address, telephone number, e-mail address, IP addresses, information on your use of the website or other personal information you have explicitly provided it to us e.g. by filling in a mail or subscription form. 

We may process such information in order to provide you with the services on our website, process your requests and to ensure that the information is treated diligently e.g. by access restricting our systems. Ramboll Group A/S is thus collecting and processing your personal data for legitimate interests of Ramboll Group A/S and your personal data is processed based on Ramboll Group A/S’ interest in processing the personal data, which overrides your interests. 

All data will be treated as confidential information and will only be used for the purpose as set out above.  

Your personal data may be accessed by Ramboll group entities worldwide on a need to know basis. Ramboll Group A/S use external service providers for hosting and operating this website and your personal data may be accessed and processed by such service providers strictly on behalf of Ramboll Group A/S.

Please be informed that the level of data protection as currently applied and enforced in countries outside the European Union does not conform to the level of data protection for personal data currently applied and enforced within the European Union. The transfer of data between Ramboll group entities will be based on Binding Corporate Rules or the European Commission’s Standard Contractual Clauses. You may request a copy of the Binding Corporate Rules by contacting privacy@ramboll.com.

Ramboll Group A/S may engage third party service providers that will have access to and process your personal data. If such third-party services providers process your personal data outside of the EU/EEA, such transfer of personal data will either be subject to the EU-U.S. Privacy Shield or the European Commission’s standard contractual clauses. You can request a copy of the agreement covering the transfer of personal data by contacting privacy@ramboll.com.

Ramboll Group A/S will keep your personal data for up to two years, unless Ramboll Group A/S is required under applicable law to keep your personal data for a longer period of time.

You can obtain further information on the personal data which Ramboll Group A/S stores and processes about you by contacting [privacy@ramboll.com](mailto:privacy@ramboll.com). Further, you may object to your personal data being processed or request that your personal data is rectified. If you wish to object to your personal data being processed or have your data rectified, please contact [privacy@ramboll.com](mailto:privacy@ramboll.com) with this message. Further, if you have any complaints about Ramboll Group A/S’ processing of your personal data, you may contact the Danish Data Protection Agency.
